Now, as you study math
...  At some point, there
comes a moment when you face a wall.  From a certain day on, my scores
won't go up no matter how much I study.  I
keep solving practice problems and listening to lectures, but my
grades usually stop around Grade 3.
Even if I manage to break through that, they stop right there at the low end of Grade 2
.  But the interesting thing is that
even though the timing of when the wall appears varies from person to person, the
method of breaking through it is almost fixed
.  In today's video, I will explain the
specific methods for breaking through walls assigned to each level, based
on my two experiences of actually breaking through walls
.   There were
exactly two moments when I felt my math skills had truly leveled up
.  The first is when
moving up from grades 2 or 3 to the latter half of grade 1
, and the second is when moving up from the latter half of grade 1 to the
Manjeong-gwon.  However,
how I broke through the wall in each instance is
really important in studying math
.  First of all, I
would like to tell you a little about what kind of student I have been up until now.  Up until this point, I
typically took a lot of lectures and attended academies
.  But there is something important, you know.
Nothing remained in my mind
.  Because I keep reviewing concepts I've already seen and
listening to lectures over and over,
by the time I finish solving a whole book of problems, I've completely forgotten the beginning parts
.  It's not in my head.
So, I didn't feel like the concepts were organized in my head
at all; instead, whenever
I saw a problem, I was just barely managing to piece together and apply the concepts I had learned at the time
.  At the time, I didn't realize that I was
studying incorrectly
.  Because I thought I was working
hard in my own way.  But there are probably
a lot of students who feel guilty about this
.  The reason is simple.  Actually,
seeing the concept and understanding it means the concept has
become mine.  It is
completely different from being able to apply it.  In mathematics, for a
concept to truly become yours, it
must become an output, not just input—that is, listening or reading.  The
best way to practice is blank-page review,
or you can
also review by explaining it out loud.  In my
consulting work, I
strongly
emphasize writing things down and explaining them verbally.  yes.  The method is actually
simple.  For print review, after class,
simply close your book and explain what you learned today as if a
student were sitting next to you. For blank
paper review,
write down the subheadings and simple keywords on a blank sheet of paper and print out the concepts you know from that unit from
beginning to end
.  The important thing here is that you must
study by considering any missing items not as things you forgot, but as things you do not know, and by dreaming of self-perception.   There is
one point here that students have questions about.  Uh, shouldn't I be
solving at least one more problem instead of doing a blank check
?  I also actually have to
solve a lot of problems, just like on YouTube.  Especially in mathematics,
they emphasize a lot that rote learning is really important.  But to start with the
conclusion regarding this question, it is old age.
To be precise, it’s not that you only do blank-page reviews and don’t solve problems; you
need to do both blank-page reviews and solve problems sufficiently.  Because while
blank-page review itself isn't the
main study method that dramatically improves grades, it is an
essential
preparatory process for that.  To shoot a gun, you have to
load the bullets.  It is like
students who have reached grade 3
constantly skipping lectures and solving problems without loading up, only to make the
same mistakes every day.
Since problem-solving essentially involves utilizing concepts, if those concepts are
not in your head, you will
naturally end up solving problems by type through rote memorization without utilizing them
.  But what is really
important here is that I am absolutely not saying you should just keep doing blank-page reviews
.  If
math ends with blank-page review, that is
meaningless.  Blank paper review is a means to engrain concepts in your mind,
and the key is the process of
independently retrieving and applying those concepts to problems
.  So,
the order I recommend to students in the high 3rd grade or lower is exactly
this.  First, completely block the concept clarification through blank-page review
.  Then,
right away, focusing on the easy past exam questions, you know, the ones worth 3 or low
4 points.  You need to apply it immediately due to those problems
.  At this point, you do
n't need to listen to all the lectures on these past exam questions; instead, you should selectively review only the problems you get stuck on and
handle the rest primarily using the answer key.  At that time, the situation I was in was that even though I
had just taken the pitching class two or three times, I couldn't even
properly explain the definition of differentiability.   When asked to
explain, I could only stammer and
answer to the extent of, "when the graph is smooth," or something like that.  Come to think of it now, it does
n't make sense that a student like this is good at math.  But that is the
reality for the average student.  There are
definitely many students who feel guilty about this.  The
second wall.  So, you know those students ranging from the early 2nd grade to the
late 1st grade?
When these students move into the perfect score range, their
weapons change.  From here on, it's ultimately just a
shepherd.  However, at this stage, it must not be a
meaningless, mindless shepherd, but a structured,
maintenance-oriented shepherd.
I can guarantee that in order to
break through the Grade 1 barrier and settle into the perfect score range,
and beyond that to
reach a stable level of satisfaction, sheer volume of practice
is absolutely essential.  yes.  You
really need to solve a lot of problems, at least 30 a day
.  Actually, while preparing for the college entrance exam during my senior year of high school, I made sure to
solve at least 30 problems every single day, and as a result, I solved over
50 sets of N-series math problems alone, including subjective questions
.  But if
I just solve about 50 practice problems without any real effort, will I
definitely get a perfect score?  Absolutely
not.  Even if you solve 100 workbooks, you might still be in the
same grade range.  The
most important attitude you should have at this point is
scenario mapping.   If I were to
define scenario mapping in a single sentence, it would be
this.  It is a habit of interpreting the conditions
and mentally
planning the flow to the goal before solving a problem.  Here is
where something important comes up.  The problem is
not to solve it with your hands, but to determine the direction in your head and
just do the calculations with your hands
.  Now, since many students have been asking what the
difference is between scenario mapping and mental arithmetic,
I’ve brought question number 11 from last year’s CSAT here
.
In problems like this, most students immediately
start by mindlessly setting a and r and expanding the sequence, assuming it is a geometric sequence.  But to get a perfect score, you have to do the
exact opposite.
First, I stare intently at the problem.  I'm
drawing up a scenario.  And
first, let's look at how these conditions are connected in a structure
.  Instead of reaching out first,
think of various possible scenarios in your head and verify them one by one to determine which one is the best
.
There are likely many different scenarios for this problem.  Okay, first of all, as
I just mentioned, there is the
scenario where you just take A and R and solve it.
Also, if you observe carefully, you will see that the
left group and the right group are exactly the same, but they are
grouped with a spacing of exactly three spaces.  In other words, if you
multiply this by R³,
you can observe that it becomes the right group
.  As I visualize the scenario in my head
.  Then, a single flow immediately
comes to mind.  Since the P clump and the clump will be erased, once they are erased,
I will eventually be able to calculate the r value.
What I mean by "being erased" is, let's call this block on the left a
star.  Then
multiplying an asterisk by r raised to the power of 3 is
6.  It's exactly the same as this.   So
, what comes out of here?   It's being marked with an
asterisk, right?  Since the star is
not 0, the r-th power becomes 2.   If
you look it up, you've solved all the problems, right?  Now, this is question
number 12 from the CSAT, and the problem was solved very easily just by
thinking about a scenario and designing the flow for a moment
.  Number 12 isn't that easy of a
problem; it's actually a near-killer problem.
Looking at this problem alone, you think, "What is this?"  Even if I do that, it gets
solved the same way anyway. It just
takes a long time and only reduces the calculation by one line
.  You might have that thought
.  But...  It’s just that I
brought a slightly easier mid-level killer problem; there are
problems that are just a little more difficult.  When faced with
killer problems like numbers 15 or 22,
designing a scenario like this at least once and whether or not you picked up a fan makes a
huge difference in the length of the solution.  Furthermore, it
becomes a factor that determines whether or not this problem can be solved.
Instead of doing mental calculations, try to predict in your head before touching the problem and figure out
how to
solve it.  You practice designing that flow, do
n't you?  Then your math skills will
improve tremendously.  This is
scenario mapping, everyone.  You
design first, not calculate.
Now, you can maintain this thought process exactly as it is
.  Once you
enter the engine in that state, from then on, you just really need to
unleash Je and Simho like crazy
.  Because now, shepherding is no longer just
meaningless, simple labor, but training that
explosively increases one's scenario design ability
.  When I was in active service, from about
April to August, I
released a lot of Angels. I
really released about 50 Angels at a time using this method.
Including the organizing body.  In the process, I
became convinced that I had truly broken through the wall of perfection, and I even became convinced that as long as I didn't make any mistakes, there was
n't a single problem within the scope of the CSAT that I couldn't solve
.  You get
that conviction once you start brushing your teeth, don't you?
Then, my mindset changes completely in the exam room
.  The calculations also
become much more accurate.  You can also use time more
stably.  Now, if you’ve
listened this far and had an "aha" moment,
congratulations.  You have
taken the first step toward an explosive score increase
.  However, while you are
solving problems on your own, there will definitely be moments when you are unsure about how far you
should go with the scenario web or if you are doing it right
.  For those students, I have
recorded a lesson in a tutoring format demonstrating my thought process of scenario mapping for all the past exam questions from the Suwon Sutu dictionary since the revision.  To
read you just a few representative reviews, I was a student who solved math problems without thinking about what I was
observing, what it meant, what I
needed to do, how the answer came about, or whether or not the
answer was correct. However, by
explaining the thought process of observing the problem and setting up a scenario, as well as the rationale, step by step and making me
understand, I learned the attitude to approach math problems
.  In my
opinion, this is the true core of mathematical ability
. I believe this ability is a factor that improves fundamental mathematical skills themselves, far more so than skills or
knowing a lot of practical concepts
.  As for the other student, well, to put it simply, it
felt like receiving the attention of a medical student who communicates well.  There is also a review stating that as they
took the course while internalizing the attitudes and perspectives taught, they
felt confident that by the time they completed the course with regular review, they would be able to conquer the intermediate and killer questions
.  I have only one purpose for creating this class
.  I am correct because I want you to
reconstruct my thought process exactly as I solve math problems
.  The class was so elegant, and the
response from the students who took it last year was very
positive.  yes.  However, if you are currently in the
stage of taking concept lectures, do not enroll just because you want to right away. Instead, wait until you
reach the moment, just like me, when you feel like you have hit a wall in math and decide, "I need to
break through this barrier to get a Grade 1."   I
recommend taking the course when that moment comes.  Then, I believe it can
clearly serve as a catalyst to break down that wall
.  Okay, let's wrap things up one
last time.  Breaking through the math wall
ultimately requires four steps to be
aligned.  The first blank-page
review converts concepts into a printable format
.  Apply the second easy past exam question
.  Now, since blank-page review is a means and
application is the key, this requirement must be
included.  Third, afterwards,
perfect the material to the point where past exam questions can be explained using scenario mapping. Fourth,
build up your signal through insane shepherdship that involves structure and scenario mapping practice.  Now, if you study like this,
anyone can break through the wall of math
.  I hope you study in the right direction
.  yes.  It
was Ark until now.  thank you